> > Jem Young: 但我还有个问题。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But I still have a problem.
我不喜欢每次都要运行 node.appjs 。
I don't like that I have to run
node.appjs every single time.
如果重新启动服务器，会发生什么情况 ?
What happens if I restart my server?
如果我杀了它怎么办
What happens if I just kill it?
如果我的电脑在这一点上睡觉而壳出口了怎么办
What happens if my computer goes to
sleep at this point and the shell exits,
这意味着它会杀死所有正在运行的程序
which means it'll kill every
program that's running.
我们需要某种管理者，这样我们就可以使用流程管理器。
We need some sort of manager so
we're going to use a process manager.
流程管理器只是一种保持应用程序正常运行的方法。
And a process manager is just a way of
keeping your application up and running.
它可以处理错误，它将处理重新启动。
It can handle errors, it handles restarts.
假设您的代码中有一个抛出未处理的异常的位置。
Let's say you have a place in your code
that throws a non handled exception.
在节点中执行哪些操作 ?
What does that do in Node?
这会害死人的
That'll just kill the program.
因此，您需要一些处理该问题，然后正常重新启动的服务。
So you need some sort of service that
handles that and then restarts gracefully.
工作就是让过程不断地不断地运行
And it's job is to keep the process up and
running constantly and
它是在后台做的
it does it in the background.
今天我们要用这个练习用 pm2
So today we're gonna use, for
this exercise we're gonna use pm2.
你也可以永远的用一个程序，永远是好的，
You can also use a program called
forever and forever is good,
它是一个完美的流程管理器 pm2 是一个更全面的特点
it's a perfectly fine process manager,
pm2 is a bit more full featured.
而且它的使用更干净。
And it's a little bit cleaner to use.
但是，可以自由使用您想要的任何流程管理器，但在这种情况下，我们将使用 pm2。
But feel free to use any process manager
you want, but in this case we'll use pm2.
我们又要再来一次了
So we're gonna us npm again.
因为我们正在进行全球性的安装，我们必须使用 sudo 命令。
And because we're doing a global install,
we're gonna have to use the sudo command.
因此 sudo npm i -g for global pm2。
So sudo npm i -g for global pm2.
>> Jem Young: 是吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes?
>> 演讲者 2: 我被告知的经验法则是避免安装全局。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So rule of thumb I've
been told is avoid installing global.
这是一个例外，其中- >> Jem Young: 是。
This is an exception where-
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes.
>> 演讲者 2: 例外情况是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: What are the exceptions?
何时安全使用全局安装?
When is it safe to use a global install?
>> Jem Young: 当您需要从任何目录全局运行它时。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: When you need to run
it globally from any directory.
因为这不是，说我还有四，五个节点应用程序在运行，
Because this isn't, let's say I had four
or five other node applications running,
我想要 pm2 来存取所有这些
I want pm2 to access all of that.
所以，安装和本地都不太有道理，因为我们没有
So installing and locally wouldn't make as
much sense because we didn't then we have
把所有东西都管到节点模块上
to pipe everything into node modules,
things like that.
但这一点非常好。
But that's an excellent point.
你一般都不想在全球做事情，除非你必须这样做。
You generally don't want to do
things globally unless you have to.
如果你想在全球范围内
If you wanna run things globally but
从本地目录中，您可以使用称为 MPX的内容。
from the local directory you
can use something called MPX.
先在你的地方看看然后上去
Which will look at first in your local and
then move up.
但在这种情况下，我们想在全球运行，因为它的流程管理者。
But in this case, we wanna run globally
because its a process manager.
但我的问题很重要，那就是在事情的基础上。
Great question though,
that is staying on top of things.
>> Jem Young: 太棒了，那是个大安装。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Awesome,
that was a big install.
这件事还有很多事要做
Man, there's a lot to this thing,
good times.
无论如何，没有人看到正在安装的库。
Anyways, no one ever looks at
the library being installed.
如果你问我晚上的事是什么但现在不是晚上
If you asked me what are my issues
with npm, and it's not npm,
只是包装经理你不知道到底发生了什么
it's just package managers, is you
don't know what's actually going on.
你根本不知道这些包裹里有什么
You have no idea what any
of these packages do.
这也是我们的信任
Again it's trust,
互联网是建立在信任的基础上的，我相信这一点是正确的。
the Internet's built on trust and
I trust that this is working correctly.
明天我们要运行更高版本的节点
Tomorrow we're going to run
a higher version of node,
就因为我喜欢使用现代的功能
just because I like to
use modern features.
但我们使用的是基线安装
But we're using the baseline
install that came with,
因为我们是从适当的爬虫类中安装的，它们总是在后面，我不知道为什么。
because we installed from the apt repo,
they're always behind, I don't know why.
但今天我不想改变这一点
But today I didn't wanna
go into how to change that,
如何指向其他版本。
how to point that to a different version.
但明天我们可能要运行 10或 12 节点，或者 LTS 版本的任何版本。
But tomorrow we're gonna run probably node
10, or 12, or whatever the LTS version is.
但今天我们没事
But for today we're okay.
>> Jem Young: 所以让我们开始吧，开始 pm2。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So
let's go ahead and start pm2.
所以 pm2 启动 app.js。
So pm2 start app.js.
>> Jem Young: Cool ， and
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool, and
它现在正在以 0 标识运行，因为它现在只是在运行。
it's now running with id 0 because
it's only thing running right now.
好的现在我可以去做我想做的事
What's nice is now,
I can go do whatever I want and
它只是在后台运行
it's just running in the background.
如果它崩溃，它将尽最大努力保持它的状态，以防它发生。
If it crashes it's going to do its
absolute best to keep it up, just in case.
但要确保它在服务器重新启动时启动，
But to make sure that it starts
when the server restarts,
因为现在，如果服务器重新启动，那么我们仍然必须启动 pm2 启动 app.js。
because right now if the server restarts,
we still have to go pm2 start app.js.
我们可以修改 pm2 启动文件，以便它创建一个始终启动的守护程序
We can modify the pm2 startup file so that
it creates a daemon that will always start
启动服务器时的应用程序。
our application when we start the server.
所以我们会说 pm2 启动
So we'll say pm2 startup.
>> Jem Young: Cool。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool.
>> Jem Young: 我认为我不需要设置启动脚本。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I don't think I
need to set the startup script.
我想它是给我的但我们会检查的
I think it does it for
me, but we'll check.
所以我现在要做的就是控制版本
So what I'm gonna do now,
we get to version control,
确保我做对了
make sure I did that right.
我们可能要把它复制并粘贴在其中。
We may actually have to copy and
paste this in.
但我不认为我最后一次碰到这种情况时就必须这样做。
But I don't think I had to do that
when I ran this through last time.
但我要做的是测试一下我的服务器
But what I'm gonna do to test this out,
is I'm gonna take down my server.
最快的方法是你是否正确的做了
The fastest way to find out
if you did things correctly.
我要把它关掉好吗 ?
And I'm gonna turn it off, yeah, turn off.
它需要第二个很酷的
It takes a second, cool.
服务器关闭，让它重新开启。
The server is off and
let's turn it back on.
给我一分钟好吗
Give it a minute,
is it up and running yet?
我只是用了下扣子
I just used just the off button.
>> Jem Young: 这不太有用，因为你还，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Which, it's not terribly
useful because you still, and
数字海洋会告诉你这个，你还在发单。
Digital Ocean will tell you this,
you're still getting billed.
只要你把它关了
Just cuz you turn it off,
并不意味着你被释放了就意味着它没在运行
doesn't mean you deallocated yourself,
just means it's not running.
一个重要的区别是你可以把它关掉然后好好想想
An important distinction,
cuz you might turn it off and think well,
我不需要服务器他们还在给你充电
I won't need the server,
they're still charging you.
所以你的里程可能不同
[LAUGH] So your mileage may vary.
服务器上了吗
Okay is the server up?
可能要花一秒
It might take a second.
So pm2 status， >> Jem Young: And
So pm2 status,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And
我们的应用程序正在运行，所以 pm2 保存。
we got the app running, so pm2 save.
>> Jem Young: 酷，现在它被拯救了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool, so now it's saved.
当服务器重新启动时， pm2 将像以前一样启动并运行。
When the server restarts, pm2 will
get up and running as it did before.
这其实是个很重要的交易
This is actually a pretty big deal
cuz you'll forget to do it and
你就会杀了你的服务器
you will kill your server.
一切都正常了看看这个妈妈你就像我什么都没看见
Everything is working, check this out mom,
and you're like, I don't see anything,
你是个失败的儿子和工程师
you're a failure as a son and
as a engineer.
不这不重要我妈不管什么都爱我
No, that doesn't matter,
my mom loves me no matter what.
>> [LAUGH] >> Jem Young: [LAUGH] 也这样
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: [LAUGH] That's way too
很多信息。
much information.